A Finding Aid to the Pietro Lazzari Papers, 1878-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lazzpiet
Archives of American Art
Pietro Lazzari papers
1878-1998
AAA.lazzpiet
Archives of American Art
12.4 Linear feet
The papers of muralist and sculptor, Pietro Lazzari, measure 12.4 linear feet and date from 1878 to 1998. The papers document Lazzari's life and career through biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes, writings, artwork, photographs, and printed material.
Lazzari, Pietro
Biographical Note
Pietro Lazzari was born in Rome, on May 15, 1898. At the age of 15, he was apprenticed to Roman sculptor, Jerace. Four years on the Italian front in World War I interrupted his studies, until he could return to the Ornamental School of Rome, where he received a Master Artist degree in 1922. Lazzari's first solo exhibition was at the Theatre of the Independents in Rome. He was also employed by newspaper Il Messaggero to illustrate articles with athletes' portraits.
Lazzari visited the United States in 1925, exhibiting in a group show at the New Gallery in the New York the following year. He also married American social worker Elizabeth Paine in 1926. After four more trips between the United States and Italy, he permanently settled in New York City in 1929. In addition to participating in major art exhibitions, he was hired by a New York newspaper to make courtroom sketches at the Lindbergh kidnapping trial. Divorcing his first wife in 1932, Lazzari married Evelyn Cohen in 1934, and became a U.S. citizen in 1936. Between 1936 and 1942, he worked on four post office murals for the U.S. Section of Fine Arts and began experimentation that led to his own method of painting in polychrome concrete.
In 1942, Lazzari moved to Washington, D.C. and participated in the war effort. He also taught painting and sculpture at The American University, and from 1948 to 1950, he headed the Art Department at Dumbarton College. In 1950, he received a Fulbright Fellowship for research in techniques of Etruscan Art.
Lazzari is known for his bronze busts of humanitarians, most notably Pope Paul VI, Adlai Stevenson, and Eleanor Roosevelt. Represented by the Betty Parsons Gallery in New York, he was also very active in the Washngton, D.C. art community, where he was represented by the Caresse Crosby Gallery.
Pietro Lazzari died on May 1, 1979 in Bethesda, Maryland.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of muralist and sculptor, Pietro Lazzari, measure 12.4 linear feet and date from 1878 to 1998. The collection documents Lazzari's life and career through biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes, writings, artwork, photographs, and printed material.
Biographical material includes biographical sketches and various identification documents. Correspondence comprises letters exchanged between Lazzari, family members, and colleagues and includes about a hundred letters concerning post office murals in several states.
Notebooks contain drawings and annotated diagrams in addition to notes on artwork and designs for inventions. Writings are both by and about Lazzari and include autobiographical material. Artwork includes sketchbooks, loose sketches, prints, and paintings.
Almost a quarter of the collection consists of photographs which include images of Lazzari, his family and colleagues, and gallery installations. Also found are photographs of several notable individuals.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as ten series according to material type. For each series, material within folders is arranged chronologically. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1880-1980 (box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1895-1998, undated (boxes 1-2; 1.7 linear ft.)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1925-1993, undated (box 2; 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 4: Notes, 1915-1979, undated (boxes 3, 13, OV 14; 1 linear ft.)
Series 5: Writings, 1910-1979, undated (box 4, 13; 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 6: Artwork, 1918-1979, undated (boxes 4-5, 13, OV 14; 0.9 linear ft.)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1905-1994, undated (boxes 5-8, 13, OV 14; 3.8 linear ft.)
Series 8: Photographs, 1878-1980, undated (boxes 8-13, MGP 1, MGP 4; 3.8 linear ft.)
Series 9: Motion Picture Film, undated (box 12; 1 folder)
Series 10: Artifact, undated (box 12; 1 folder)
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art is one sound tape reel of a transcribed interview with Pietro Lazzari, conducted by Harlan Phillips in 1964.
Provenance
The Pietro Lazzari papers were donated to the Archives of American Art in 1989 by Evelyn C. Lazzari, widow of Pietro Lazzari, and in 1998 by her estate.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Apollo 17 (Spacecraft); Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-; Phillips, Duncan, 1886-1966; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Rust, John D.; Stevenson, Adlai E., (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Motion pictures (visual works); Muralists--Washington (D.C.); Paintings; Photographs; Portrait sculpture, American--Washington (D.C.); Prints; Sculptors--Washington (D.C.); Sculpture, American--Washington (D.C.); Sketchbooks; Slides (photographs); Works of art
- Biographical Material, 1880-1980; Series 1; (box 1; 4 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes biographical sketches, miscellaneous identification and membership cards, certificates of merit, and an international driver's license. Also included is a military record book of Lazzari's father, Pietro.
  - Biographical sketches (40), 1946-1980; (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous biographical material for Lazzari, 1923-1976 (Box 1)
  - Military record book of Lazzari's father, Pietro, 1880-1882 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1895-1998, undated; Series 2; (boxes 1-2; 1.7 linear feet)
  This series consists of letters exchanged between Lazzari, family members, and colleagues. Over one hundred letters from the Federal Works Agency and the Treasury Department Section of Painting and Sculpture concern post office murals for towns in Florida, New Jersey, and North Carolina. Five letters from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration contain 23 photographs of astronauts Eugene A. Cernan, Ronald E. Evans, and Harrison H. Schmitt preparing for an Apollo 17 mission to the moon. Lazzari also received at least one letter each from Jacqueline Kennedy, Duncan Phillips, Eleanor Roosevelt, industrialist John Rust, and socialist Norman Thomas.
  See index for List of Selected Correspondents from Series 2.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  Index
  List of Correspondents in Series 2
  Aguilera, Francisco: undated (1 letter)
  Albergo Saturnia, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Alberts: Russell Alberts-Laura Langdon Antiques: undated (1 letter)
  Alexander Gallery: undated (1 letter)
  Allied Publications, Inc.: 1965 (1 letter)
  Alterman, Selma: undated (1 letter)
  Ambasciata d'Italia: 1950-1973 (3 letters)
  Ambasciatore d'Italia: undated and 1971 (2 letters)
  America-Italy Society: 1956 (1 letter)
  American Academy in Rome: 1955 (2 letters)
  American Artists Professional League: 1949-1955 (3 letters)
  American Battle Monuments Commission: 1959 (1 letter)
  American Commission for Cultural Exchange with Italy (Fulbright grant): 1950-1954 (2 letters)
  American Federation of Arts: 1951-1956 (2 letters)
  American Red Cross: 1943-1945 (6 letters)
  American University: 1947-1967 (5 letters)
  Amici, Alfredo: 1948-1959 (6 letters)
  Amministrazione Erdi M.se Saverio Patrizi: 1969 (2 letters)
  Andori, Adolfo: 1913-1916 (3 letters)
  Anderson, Wayne V.: 1956 (1 letter)
  Andrade, Victor: undated (1 letter)
  Angelelli, Augusta: 1972 (1 letter)
  Angiolillo, Giuseppe: 1967-1972 (9 letters)
  Anson, Cherrill: 1998 (1 letter)
  Appleby, J. Scott: 1952-1961 (9 letters); see Life Insurance Company of Georgia
  Aquil, Preta: 1921 (1 letter)
  Architectural League of New York: 1955 (3 letters)
  Aristide, Zio (?): 1926 (1 letter)
  Arndal, Kersten: 1970-1977 (2 letters)
  Art Direction magazine: 1956 (1 letter)
  Art in Federal Buildings, Inc.: 1943 (1 letter)
  Art Institute of Chicago: 1944-1956 (11 letters)
  Artists Equity Association: undated and 1949-1972 (7 letters)
  Artists for Victory: 1942-1943 (7 letters including a prospectus for "America in the War" exhibition)
  Artists of Washington, D.C.: undated (1 letter)
  Artist's Guild of Washington: 1960 (1 letter)
  Associated Architects & Engineers: 1957 (1 letter)
  Associated Artists Gallery of Washington: 1961 (1 letter)
  Associazione Artistica Internazionale: 1950 (1 letter)
  Atomic Energy Clearing House: 1963 (1 letter)
  Bache, Martha Moffett: 1949 (1 letter)
  Backus, Florence: 1955 (1 letter)
  Bader: Franz Bader Gallery: 1950-1976 (3 letters)
  Baltimore Museum of Art: undated and 1948-1956 (8 letters); see Breeskin, Adelyn
  Banca Commerciale Italiana: 1969 (2 letters)
  Bankok Insustries, Inc.: 1972 (1 letter)
  Bashir, Mir: 1955 (2 letters)
  Bazzanella, Albina: 1926-1928 (2 letters)
  Bedi-Rassy Art Foundry: 1952-1962 (4 letters)
  Beer, Elsie: 1926-1928 (3 letters)
  Bergeson, Mrs.: 1951 (1 letter)
  Berkman, Jack: 1949 (1 letter)
  Berkowitz, Ida and Leon (Workshop Center of the Arts): 1953-1955 (2 letters)
  Berrier, Jean: 1971 (1 letter)
  Betts, Luici: 1928 (1 letter)
  Birnbaum, Britta: 1963 (1 letter)
  Blake, Margaret Day: [1956] (1 letter)
  Blanc, Peter: undated and 1948-1950 (4 letters)
  Bly?, Edith: undated (1 letter)
  Borea, Raimondo: 1971 (1 letter)
  Borzani, Gastone: 1918 (1 letter)
  Boulner, Bartlet: 1927 (1 letter)
  Bowen, Elizabeth: undated (1 letter)
  Brambilla, Helen: 1945 (1 letter of recommendation for Lazzari)
  Breeskin, Adelyn D. (Baltimore Museum of Art): 1953-1961 (4 letters)
  Broders, Dr. Hy: 1941 (envelope only; enclosing photo of unidentified friends)
  Brooklyn Museum: 1956 (1 letter)
  Brooks Memorial Art Gallery: 1952 (2 letters); see Rust, John
  Broude & Hochberg: 1969 (1 letter)
  Brown, James W.: 1934 (1 letter)
  Bruce, Edward: mentioned in 3 letters dated 1938-1943
  Bryn Mawr Club of Washington: 1961 (1 letter)
  Buckingham Palace: 1971 (1 letter)
  Bureau of Copyrights and Patents, Library of Congress: 1936-1955 (3 letters)
  Burleighfield International Arts Centre: 1977 (1 letter)
  Buxton, P. S.: 1969 (1 letter)
  Cahill, Holger: see Works Progress Administration
  Caldwell, Henry Bryan: 1951 (1 letter from Lazzari)
  Calfee, William H.: 1967 (1 letter)
  California: University of California at Berkeley: 1986 (1 letter)
  California: University of California at Los Angeles: 1970 (1 letter)
  Canali, Paola: undated (1 letter)
  Cani, Edward: undated (1 letter)
  Capital Park Apartments: mentioned in a letter dated 1962
  Carbela: 1929 (1 letter)
  Carbonati, Antonio: 1927 (2 letters)
  Carnassale, Enrico: 1914-1916 (2 letters)
  Carolan, Anna B. (The Little Gallery): 1947 (2 letters)
  Casella, E. and M.: 1917-1918 (4 letters)
  Caserma, Luisa.: 1914-1917 (2 letters)
  Catholic University of America: 1964 (1 letter)
  Caulfield, Patricia: 1949 (1 letter)
  Central States Joint Board: 1977 (1 letter)
  Chapel, Maria: 1970-1973 (3 letters)
  Chase, Ralph H.: 1959-1961 (2 letters)
  Child, Col. Sargent B.: 1968 (1 letter from Corcoran)
  City of New York Department of Correction (Riker's Island mural): 1936-1937 (2 letters)
  Civil Service Commission Club: 1949 (1 letter)
  Clark, Joseph (Senator from Pennsylvania): 1962 (1 letter)
  Clemens, Cyril ( Mark Twain Journal): 1971 (1 letter)
  Cohen, Evelyn: see Lazzari, Evelyn
  Cohen, Lester: 1956 (1 letter)
  Colladay, Edward F.: 1932 (1 letter)
  Conant, Howard (New York University): 1956 (1 letter)
  Connolley, Robert Emmet: 1947-1950 (8 letters)
  Console Generale d'Italia: 1965 (1 letter)
  Constantino, C.: 1967 (1 letter)
  Cook, Elizabeth: [1946] (1 letter)
  Cooke: Hereward Lester Cooke Foundation: 1974-1975 (3 letters); see National Aeronautics and Space Administration; see National Gallery of Art
  Cooper, Alice J.: 1927 (1 letter)
  Corcoran Gallery of Art: undated and 1951-1981 (37 letters)
  Corsi, Emma and W. Edward: 1928 (1 letter)
  Cosgrove, Jessica (Mrs. John O'Hara Cosgrove): 1928-1930 (22 letters)
  Cosgrove, John O'Hara (editor of New York World): undated and 1927-1929 (7 letters)
  Costintin, Celestino and Emilia: 1916-1971 (6 letters)
  Cotzia, Pasquale: 1966-1968 (2 letters)
  Coughlin, Clarence John: 1948 (1 letter)
  Crimi: undated (1 letter)
  Crosby, Caresse (Crosby Gallery of Modern Art): undated and 1945-1969 (14 letters)
  Crossley, Kay A.: 1966 (1 letter)
  Cullen, Amelia: undated (1 letter)
  Cusumono, Stefano: 1947-1951 (3 letters)
  Daloni, Edith B.: 1928 (1 letter)
  Damer, Veffarghi: 1919 (1 letter)
  Damiani, Angelo: 1921 (1 letter)
  Dane, C. K.: 1965 (1 letter)
  Dean, Edward: 1940 (1 letter)
  Debs: Eugene V. Debs Foundation: 1965-1966 (3 letters including 6 photographs with Norman Thomas); see United Auto Workers
  de Chetelat, Mr.: mentioned in letter dated 1928
  de Chirico, Giorgio: mentioned in undated invitation from Ambasciatore d'Italia
  DeLano, Agnes: undated (1 letter)
  De Medio, Americo: 1963-1976 (32 letters)
  De Medio, Vincenzo: undated and 1970-1977 (3 letters)
  Demiddi, Alberto: undated and 1972 (3 letters)
  De Mont, Nany and Eugene: undated (1 letter)
  Dernay, Eugene: 1945-1959 (4 letters)
  Design in Steel Award Program: 1972 (1 letter)
  Dictionary of International Biography: 1974 (1 letter)
  Diller, Burgoyne: see Federal Art Project
  Dipanfilo, Pio: 1949-1968 (10 letters)
  Di Raimondo, Vicenzo: 1920-1928 (7 letters)
  District of Columbia Board of Commissioners: 1959 (1 letter)
  District of Columbia Department of Public Welfare: 1958 (1 letter)
  District of Columbia Juvenile Court: 1964 (1 letter)
  District of Columbia Recreation Board: 1963 (1 letter)
  Dole (?), Louis: 1923 (1 letter)
  Dollinger, Josef: undated (1 letter)
  Donaldson, Leota L.: undated (2 letters)
  Donaldson, Renee: undated (1 letter)
  Douglas, Paul F.: 1951 (1 letter)
  Dretzin, S. C.: 1950 (1 letter)
  Draper, Warren A.: 1944 (1 letter)
  Dumbarton College: 1949-1951 (3 letters)
  Duncan and Duncan Chinese Shop: 1964 (1 letter)
  Dunham, Dr. G. C.: 1944 (1 letter re: portrait of Dr. Sawyer)
  Duproix, Eunice: 1928 (1 letter)
  Durbin, Jack: 1960 (1 letter)
  Editions du Griffon, Neuchatel, Suisse: 1964 (3 letters)
  Edsor, Mary: 1928 (1 letter)
  Elenbrock, Gretel: 1927 (3 letters)
  Elkins: Stella Elkins Tyler School of Fine Arts of Temple University: 1956 (1 letter)
  Eng, Ernest: 1959 (1 letter)
  Ernesto Desideri: 1915 (3 letters)
  Evening Star newspaper, Washington, D.C.: 1957 (1 letter)
  Farmers Educational and Cooperative Union: 1944 (1 letter)
  Fasola, Roberto: 1948-1949 (2 letters)
  Federal Art Project: 1938-1939 (4 letters)
  Federal Works Agency, Public Buildings Administration: 1940-1947 (70 letters re: murals for the Brevard, N.C. post office, the North Bergen, N.J. post office, and the Jasper, Florida post office, including a contract, 2 photographs, and 2 sketches for a mural)
  Federal Works Agency, Work Projects Administration: 1941-1942 (2 letters)
  Fellowship of Reconciliation and War Resisters League: [1945] (1 letter)
  Ferargil Gallery: 1941 (1 letter)
  Ferreri, Elena: 1938 (1 letter)
  Figoullo, Adriano: 1912 (1 letter)
  Fiore, Ilario and Titta: 1966-1967 (5 letters)
  Fitzwater, Aldace: 1950 (1 letter)
  Florentine Gallery: 1956 (4 letters)
  Fogle, Bruce: 1927 (1 letter)
  Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations: 1956 (1 letter)
  Force, Mrs.: undated (1 letter)
  Foreign Service of the United States of America: 1950 (3 letters)
  Foresti, Arnaldo: 1948-1949 (2 letters)
  Fortas, Abe: 1956 (1 letter)
  Fortune magazine: 1944-1956 (2 letters)
  Francis, Emily A.: 1951 (3 letters)
  Franco, Johan: 1966 (2 letters)
  Frankel, Samuel: undated (1 letter)
  Freeman: Carl M. Freeman Associates, Inc.: 1963 (1 letter)
  Frisine, Robert: 1967 (1 letter)
  Frost, Phillip: 1981 (1 letter)
  Fujita, Mr.: 1957 (1 letter)
  Fulbright grant: see American Commission for Cultural Exchange with Italy
  Fuller, Eve Alsman (Miami, Fl. post office): 1938 (1 letter)
  Gabetti: undated (1 letter)
  Galarza, Ernesto and Mae: (National Farm Labor Union; National Agricultural Workers Union): undated and 1944-1978 (27 letters); see Landon School for Boys; see Perkins, Milo
  Galerie Internationale: 1965 (1 letter)
  Galerie Schindler: undated and 1965-1972 (12 letters)
  Gallaudet College: 1963-1970 (14 letters, including a contract)
  Gallenga: 1951 (1 letter)
  Gaspari, Mario P.: 1966 (1 letter)
  Georgetown University Fine Arts Club: 1960 (1 letter)
  George Washington University: 1965 (1 letter)
  Giovannetti, Alberto: 1966 (1 letter)
  Giovanni, Sebastiani: 1921 (1 letter)
  Giricosnelli, Emilio: 1918 (1 letter)
  Gobbi, Adolfo: 1928 (1 letter)
  Goldberg, Dorothy and Arthur: 1964-1965 (3 letters)
  Goldsmith, Alberto R.: 1947-1968 (3 letters)
  Gonzales, Angelino: 1951-1975 (11 letters)
  Gotham Book Mart: 1968 (1 letter)
  Graham, John: 1948 (1 letter)
  Granati, Pasquale: 1918 (1 letter)
  Grand Central Art Galleries: 1956 (1 letter)
  Grant, Blanche C.: undated (1 letter)
  Grebanier, Barnard: 1961 (1 letter)
  Greene, Hope Margaret: 1926-[1927] (2 letters)
  Gualdi, Luigi: 1947-1949 (11 letters)
  Guarino, A.: undated letters to Mabel McMahon and Guiolitta Sartori
  Guggenheim: John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation: 1937-1971 (5 letters)
  Guggenheim: Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum: 1956-1960 (3 letters)
  Gutheim, Frederick: 1956 (1 letter)
  Haarlem House, Inc.: 1926 (1 letter)
  Hahn, Rosemarie E.: 1961 (1 letter)
  Halle, Kay: 1972 (1 letter)
  Hammerle, Brooke: 1966 (1 letter)
  Hansen, Jane: 1954 (1 letter)
  Hardman, Virginia: undated (1 letter)
  Harrison & Abramovitz, Architects: 1956 (1 letter)
  Harrison, Charles H.: 1949 (1 letter)
  Hart, Earl: mentioned in an undated letter
  Hartley, Bettina: undated (1 letter)
  Hartman Galleries, Inc.: 1973 (1 letter)
  Hayward: City of Hayward, California: 1965 (1 letter)
  Health, Education, and Welfare Employees' Association: 1962 (1 letter)
  Hechinger, June: undated (1 letter)
  Heilbron, Edna: 1972 (1 letter)
  Heinemann, Mark: undated (1 letter)
  Herzbrunn, Josef: 1949 (1 letter)
  Heywood, Carmen: 1948 (1 letter)
  Hollander, Cornelia: undated (1 letter)
  Holvey, Sam: undated (1 letter)
  Holy See: Permanent Observer of the Holy See: 1966 (1 letter)
  Hom Gallery: 1972 (1 letter)
  Horrocks, E. Joan: 1971 (1 letter)
  Hotel Beau Site, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Hotel de la Ville, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Hotel Hassler, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Hotel Pension Alexandra, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Hotel Windsor, Rome: 1928 (1 letter)
  Hough, Edith Louise: 1952 (1 letter)
  Illinois State Historical Library: 1965 (1 letter)
  Il Messaggero: 1928 (1 letter)
  Immigration and Naturalization Service: 1976 (1 letter)
  Institute for International Education: 1963 (1 letter)
  Institute for the Arts of the Archdiocese of Washington: 1978 (2 letters)
  Institute of Contemporary Art: 1956 (2 letters)
  Institute of Gerontology: 1970 (1 letter)
  International Directory of Arts: 1982 (1 letter)
  Isherwood, Christopher: undated (1 letter)
  Istituzione Maddalena Aulina: 1966 (1 letter)
  Jacometti, Nesto: 1972 (1 letter)
  Jaffe, Norman: 1964 (1 letter)
  Janus, Virginia: 1929 (2 letters)
  Jelleff: Frank R. Jelleff, Inc.: 1949 (1 letter)
  Jennoff?, Peter L.: undated (1 letter)
  Jewish Social Service Agency: 1967 (1 letter)
  Johnston, L. R.: 1932 (2 letters)
  Jones, Dorothea and Stuart E.: 1955 (3 letters)
  Jones, George Lewis: 1961 (1 letter)
  Jopp, Fred Gilman: 1936 (1 letter)
  Josephy, Diane ( Time): 1968 (1 letter)
  Junior Council of the Museum of Modern Art: 1956-1960 (2 letters)
  Jurin, Benjamin M.: undated (1 letter)
  Kagy, Virginia and Sheffield: 1948 (1 letter)
  Kahles, Jessie: 1940-1948 (3 letters)
  Kennedy, Jacqueline: May 19, 1960
  Letters from White House Social Secretary: 1961-1963 (5 letters)
  Kerensky, Alexander: 1965 (1 letter)
  King Features Syndicate, Inc.: 1943 (1 letter)
  King, Marion: 1952 (1 letter)
  King, Rufus: 1975 (1 letter)
  Kneifel, Mr.: 1956 (1 letter from Lazzari)
  Kramer, Herbert (Congregazione del Preziosissimo Sangue): 1950 (1 letter)
  Krishnamurti, Jack: 1959 (1 letter)
  Kurzland, Toby: 1991 (1 letter)
  La Follia: 1926 (1 letter)
  La Galleria: 1972 (1 letter)
  Landon School for Boys: 1944 (1 letter re: Ernesto Galarza)
  Landu, Consuelo: 1948 (1 letter)
  Lanier, Fanita: see Ruffiner, Willis E.
  La Revue Moderne: 1961 (3 letters)
  La Rocca, Principessa de: 1968 (1 letter)
  Latif, Bilkeer: undated (1 letter)
  Law, L. S.: 1932 (2 letters of recommendation for Lazzari)
  Lawton, Thomas: 1974 (1 letter)
  Lazzari, Attilio: 1922 (1 letter)
  Lazzari, (Grace) Elizabeth Paine: undated and 1920-1951 (69 letters)
  Letters from Pietro to Elizabeth: 1928-1929 (52 letters)
  Lazzari, Evelyn Cohen: undated and 1948-1965 (6 letters)
  Letters from Pietro to Evelyn: undated and 1932-1966 (49 letters, including one with a photograph of friends)
  Lazzari, Fernanda (sister) and Vittoria: 1915-1949 (11 letters)
  Lazzari, Leno: 1918-1929 (2 letters)
  Lebanon: Embassy of Lebanon, Washington: 1956 (1 letter)
  Lee, Amy: Nov 01, 1974 (letter from Lazzari); 1975 (1 letter)
  Lee, Dal: 1954 (1 letter)
  Lee, Pearl: undated (1 letter)
  Levy, Sid A.: undated (1 letter)
  Library of Congress: undated and 1965-1982 (6 letters)
  Licciardi, Pietro: undated (1 letter)
  Licinio Cappelli: 1949 (1 letter)
  Life Insurance Company of Georgia: 1954 (2 letters)
  Little Gallery: see Carolan, Anna B.
  Lobatini, G.: undated (1 letter)
  Loccatelli, Giulio: 1956-1958 (2 letters)
  Lombaro (?), Patricia: 1961 (1 letter)
  Loughlin, Dr. John J.: 1936-1940 (2 letters)
  Lousine, L.: undated (1 letter)
  Luccia, Enrico: undated and 1928-1977 (19 letters)
  Lucibello, Luigi: Jan 12, 1965
  Lucifero, Alfonso: Jan 13, 1912 (letter from Ministero delle Finanze)
  Macpherson, Suzanne: 1957 (2 letters)
  Maddux, Yolanda A.: undated (1 letter)
  Maezawa, Kezuko: 1956 (1 letter)
  Magrini, Livia: 1967-1970 (5 letters)
  Makovich, L.: 1950 (1 letter)
  Manca, Albino (sculptor): 1971 (1 letter)
  Mangravite, Peppino (Columbia University): 1956 (1 letter)
  Mann: Charles Z. Mann Gallery: 1966 (1 letter)
  Mannarino, Matina: 1968 (1 letter)
  Maresciallo, Mr.: undated (1 letter from Lazzari)
  Mark, Ginevra: undated (1 letter)
  Marlor, Clark S.: 1981 (1 letter)
  Marquis Company: 1950-1981 (3 letters)
  Maryland: University of Maryland: 1972 (1 letter)
  Mattei, Cristina: 1950 (a death announcement)
  Mayfield, Mrs. David: 1938 (1 letter)
  McAfee, Don: 1955-1969 (3 letters); see Watergate Construction Corp.
  McGinnis, Paul: 1988 (1 letter)
  McIlhenny, Henry P.: 1949 (1 letter)
  McIntyre, W. A.: undated (1 letter)
  McKeogh, Elsie: 1954 (1 letter)
  McKonish, Margaret: 1949 (1 letter)
  McMahon, Mabel: undated (1 letter from A. Guarino)
  Meert, Margaret Mullin: 1948 (2 letters)
  Meeting House Gallery: 1972 (1 letter)
  Meguin, A.: undated (1 letter)
  Menard, G.: 1928 (1 letter)
  Men of Achievement: 1974-1975 (2 letters)
  Mensh, Elizabeth: 1978 (1 letter)
  Merritt, Polly: undated (1 letter)
  Messina, Joseph R.: 1971 (1 letter)
  Metropolitan Museum of Art: 1951 (1 letter)
  Miami Museum of Modern Art: 1965-1968 (7 letters)
  Miki, Suizan: undated (1 letter)
  Mills, Harrington: 1933 (1 letter)
  Ming, Wang (National Art & Frame Co.): 1968 (1 letter)
  Mitchell, Austin: 1946 (1 letter)
  Montgomery County Art Association: 1961 (1 letter)
  Moore, Norman Perry: 1927-1928 (2 letters)
  Moore, Paul: 1970 (1 letter)
  Morey, Mr.: [1950] (1 letter)
  Morott, Aristodemi: 1918 (1 letter)